Guide to the Henry O. Havemeyer Collection of Portrait Prints of American Statesmen [1790]-[1955], (Bulk [1830]-[1900]) PR 25
New-York Historical Society
- Series III: Attorneys General of the United States
  - Hugh Swinton Legare, 1841 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 230)
  - John Nelson, 1843 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 230)
  - Nathan Clifford, 1846 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 230)
  - Isaac Toucey, 1848 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 230)
  - Reverdy Johnson, 1849 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 231)
  - Caleb Cushing, 1853 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 231)
  - Jeremiah S. Black, 1857 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 231)
  - Edward Bates, 1861 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 232)
  - James Speed, 1864 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 232)
  - William M. Evarts, 1868 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 232)
  - Ebenezer R. Hoar, 1869 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 232)
  - George H. Williams, 1871 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 232)
  - Edwards Pierrepont, 1875 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 233)
  - Alphonso Taft, 1876 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 233)
  - Charles Devens, 1877 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 233)
  - Wayne MacVeagh, 1881 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 234)
  - Benjamin H. Brewster, 1882 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 234)
  - Augustus Garland, 1885 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 234)
  - William H. H. Miller, 1889 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 234)
  - Richard Olney, 1893 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 234)
  - Joseph McKenna, 1897 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 234)
  - George W. Wickersham, 1909 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 234)
- Series IV: Postmasters General of the United States
  Portraits are arranged in chronological order by term served; term starting date appears in far right column. Print/portrait dates are not necessarily contemporary with term dates. Leaf/print number 6, listed under Gideon Granger, holds images of all Postmasters General from Osgood through Kendall.
  - Ebenezer Hazard, 1782 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 235)
  - Samuel Osgood, 1789 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 235)
  - Joseph Habersham, 1795 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 235)
  - Gideon Granger (among other Postmasters), 1801 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 235)
  - Return J. Meigs, Jr., 1814 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 235)
  - John McLean, 1823 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 235)
  - William T. Barry, 1829 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 236)
  - Amos Kendall, 1835 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 236)
  - Cave Johnson, 1845 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 236)
  - Nathan K. Hall, 1850 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 236)
  - James Campbell, 1853 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 237)
  - Aaron V. Brown, 1857 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 237)
  - Montgomery Blair, 1861 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 237)
  - William Dennison, 1864 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 237)
  - John A. J. Creswell, 1869 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 238)
  - Marshall Jewell, 1874 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 238)
  - James N. Tyner, 1876 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 238)
  - David M. Key, 1877 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 239)
  - Horace Maynard, 1880 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 239)
  - Thomas L. James, 1881 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 239)
  - Timothy O. Howe, 1881 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 239)
  - Frank Hatton, 1884 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 239)
  - John Wanamaker, 1889 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 240)
  - Wilson S. Bissell, 1893 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 240)
  - Charles Emory Smith, 1898 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 240)
- Series V: Secretaries of the Interior
  - Alex H. H. Stuart, 1850 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 241)
  - Robert McClelland, 1853 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 241)
  - Jacob Thompson, 1857 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 241)
  - John P. Usher, 1863 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 241)
  - James Harlan, 1865 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 241)
  - Orville H. Browning, 1866 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 241)
  - Jacob D. Cox, 1869 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 241)
  - Columbus Delano, 1870 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 242)
  - Zachariah Chandler, 1875 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 242)
  - Carl Shurz, 1877 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 243)
  - Samuel J. Kirkwood, 1881 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 243)
  - Henry M. Teller, 1882 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 243)
  - Lucius Q. C. Lamar, 1885 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 243)
  - John W. Noble, 1889 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 244)
  - Hoke Smith, 1893 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 244)
  - David R. Francis, 1896 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 244)
  - Cornelius N. Bliss, 1897 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 244)
- Series VI: Secretary of Agriculture
  There is just one print in this series.
  - Jeremiah M. Rusk, 1889 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 245)
- Series VII: Secretaries of the Navy
  - George Cabot (declined appointment), 1798 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 246)
  - Robert Smith, 1801 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 246)
  - Benjamin W. Crowninshield, 1814 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 246)
  - Samuel Southard, 1823 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 246)
  - John Branch, 1829 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 246)
  - Levi Woodbury, 1831 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 247)
  - Mahlon Dickerson, 1834 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 248)
  - James K. Paulding, 1838 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 248)
  - George E. Badger, 1841 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 248)
  - Abel Upshur, 1841 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 248)
  - John Y. Mason, 1844, 1846 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 248)
  - George Bancroft, 1845 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 249)
  - Wililam B. Preston, 1849 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 250)
  - William A. Graham, 1850 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 250)
  - John P. Kennedy, 1852 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 250)
  - James C. Dobbin, 1853 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 251)
  - Isaac Toucey, 1857 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 251)
  - Gideon Welles, 1861 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 252)
  - Gustavus Vasa Fox (Assistant Secretary), 1861 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 253)
  - Wiliam Faxon (Assistant Secretary), 1861 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 253)
  - Adolph E. Borie, 1869 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 253)
  - George M. Robeson, 1869 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 253)
  - Richard W. Thompson, 1877 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 253)
  - Nathan Goff, Jr., 1881 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 254)
  - William H. Hunt, 1881 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 254)
  - William C. Whitney, 1885 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 254)
  - Benjamin F. Tracy, 1889 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 254)
  - Hilary A. Herbert, 1893 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 254)
  - John D. Long, 1897 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 254)
  - Paul Morton, 1904 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 254)
- Series VIII: Secretaries of State
  - Thomas Jefferson, 1789 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 255)
  - Edmund Randolph, 1794 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 255)
  - Timothy Pickering, 1795 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 256)
  - John Marshall, 1800 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 257-258)
  - James Madison, 1801 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 259)
  - Robert Smith, 1809 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 259)
  - James Monroe, 1811 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 259)
  - John Quincy Adams, 1817 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 259)
  - Henry Clay (1 of 2), 1825 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 260-271)
  - Henry Clay (2 of 2), 1825 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 260-271)
  - Martin Van Buren, 1829 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 272)
  - Louis McLane, 1833 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 272)
  - John Forsyth, 1834 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 272)
  - Daniel Webster (1 of 2), 1841, 1850 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 273-283)
  - Daniel Webster (2 of 2), 1841, 1850 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 273-283)
  - Hugh Swinton Legare (ad interim, served two months), 1843 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 284)
  - Abel P. Upshur, 1843 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 284)
  - John C. Calhoun, 1844 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 285-288)
  - James Buchanan, 1845 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 289)
  - John M. Clayton, 1849 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 289)
  - Edward Everett (1 of 2), 1852 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 290)
  - Edward Everett (2 of 2), 1852 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 291)
  - William L. Marcy, 1853 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 292)
  - Lewis Cass, 1857 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 293-294)
  - Jeremiah S. Black, 1860 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 295)
  - William H. Seward, 1861 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 296-298)
  - Elihu B. Washburne, 1869 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 299)
  - Hamilton Fish, 1869 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 300)
  - Wiliam M. Evarts, 1877 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 301)
  - James G. Blaine, 1881, 1889 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 302)
  - Frederick T. Frelinghuysen, 1881 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 303)
  - Theodore Frelinghuysen (not a Secretary of State) (Offsite-box 29, Folder 303)
  - Thomas F. Bayard, 1885 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 304)
  - Walter Q. Gresham, 1893 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 304)
  - John Sherman, 1897 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 304)
  - John Hay, 1898 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 304)
  - Elihu Root, 1905 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 304)
  - Philander C. Knox, 1909 (Offsite-box 29, Folder 304)
- Series IX: Secretaries of the Treasury
  - Alexander Hamilton, 1789 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 305-306)
  - Oliver Wolcott, Jr. (Offsite-box 30, Folder 307)
  - Samuel Dexter, 1801 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 308)
  - Albert Gallatin, 1801 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 309)
  - George W. Campbell, 1814 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 309)
  - Alexander J. Dallas, 1814 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 309-310)
  - William H. Crawford, 1816 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 311)
  - Richard Rush, 1825 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 311-312)
  - Samuel D. Ingham, 1829 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 312)
  - Louis McLane, 1831 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 312)
  - William J. Duane, 1833 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 312)
  - Roger B. Taney, 1833 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 313-314)
  - Levi Woodbury, 1834 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 314)
  - Thomas Ewing, 1841 (Offsite-box 30, Folder 314)
  - Walter Forward, 1841 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 315)
  - John C. Spencer, 1843 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 315)
  - George M. Bibb, 1844 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 315)
  - Robert J. Walker, 1845 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 315)
  - William M. Meredith, 1849 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 315)
  - Thomas Corwin, 1850 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 316)
  - James Guthrie, 1853 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 316)
  - Howell Cobb, 1857 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 316)
  - Philip F. Thomas, 1860 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 316)
  - John A. Dix, 1861 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 317)
  - Salmon P. Chase, 1861 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 318-319)
  - William P. Fessenden, 1864 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 319)
  - Hugh McCulloch, 1865, 1884 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 320)
  - George S. Boutwell, 1869 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 321)
  - William A. Richardson, 1873 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 321)
  - Benjamin H. Bristow, 1874 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 321)
  - Lot M. Morrill, 1876 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 322)
  - John Sherman, 1877 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 323)
  - William Windom, 1881, 1889 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 323)
  - Charles J. Folger, 1881 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 323)
  - Walter Q. Gresham, 1884 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 323)
  - Daniel Manning, 1885 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 324)
  - Charles S. Fairchild, 1887 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 324)
  - Charles Foster, 1891 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 324)
  - John G. Carlisle, 1893 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 324)
  - Lyman J. Gage, 1897 (Offsite-box 31, Folder 324)
- Series X: Secretaries of War
  - Henry Knox, 1789 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 325)
  - Timothy Pickering, 1795 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 326)
  - James McHenry, 1796 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 326)
  - John Marshall (appointed but did not serve), 1800 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 326)
  - Samuel Dexter, 1800 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 326)
  - Henry Dearborn, 1801 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 326)
  - William Eustis, 1809 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 327)
  - John Armstrong, 1813 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 327)
  - Isaac Shelby (decline appointment), 1817 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 327)
  - John C. Calhoun, 1817 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 327)
  - James Barbour, 1825 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 327)
  - Peter B. Porter, 1828 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 327)
  - John H. Eaton, 1829 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 328)
  - Lewis Cass, 1831 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 328)
  - Benjamin F. Butler, 1837 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 328)
  - Joel R. Poinsett, 1837 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 328)
  - John Bell, 1841 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 329)
  - John McLean (declined appointment) (Offsite-box 32, Folder 329)
  - John C. Spencer, 1841 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 330)
  - William Wilkins, 1844 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 330)
  - William L. Marcy, 1845 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 330)
  - George W. Crawford, 1849 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 330)
  - Edward C. Bates (declined appointment), 1850 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 330)
  - Jefferson Davis, 1853 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 331-333)
  - John B. Floyd, 1857 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 333)
  - Joseph Holt, 1861 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 333)
  - Simon Cameron, 1861 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 333-334)
  - Edwin M. Stanton, 1862 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 334-335)
  - Ulysses S. Grant (ad interim replacement for Stanton), 1867 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 335)
  - Lorenzo Thomas (follows Stanton in office), 1868 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 335)
  - John M. Schofield, 1868 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 335)
  - John A. Rawlins, 1869 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 336)
  - William T. Sherman, 1869 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 336)
  - William W. Belknap, 1869 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 337)
  - Alphonso Taft, 1876 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 337)
  - George W. McCrary, 1877 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 337)
  - Alexander Ransey, 1879 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 338)
  - Robert T. Lincoln, 1881 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 338)
  - Redfield Proctor, 1889 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 338)
  - Stephen B. Elkins, 1891 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 338)
  - Russel A. Alger, 1897 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 338)
  - William H. Taft, 1904 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 338)
- Series XI: Supreme Court Justices
  Portraits are arranged in chronological order by term served; term dates appear in far right column. Print/portrait dates are not necessarily contemporary with term dates.
  - John Jay, 1789-1795 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 339-340)
  - John Rutledge, 1789-1797 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 340)
  - William Cushing, 1789-1810 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 341)
  - James Wilson, 1789-1798 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 341)
  - John Blair, 1789-1796 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 342)
  - James Iredell, 1790-1799 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 342)
  - Thomas Johnson, 1791-1793 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 342)
  - William Paterson, 1793-1806 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 342)
  - Samuel Chase, 1796-1811 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 343)
  - Leonard Gansevoort [not a Supreme Court Justice] (Offsite-box 33, Folder 343)
  - Oliver Ellsworth (Offsite-box 33, Folder 343-344)
  - Oliver Goldsworth [not a Supreme Court Justice] (Offsite-box 33, Folder 344)
  - Bushrod Washington, 1798-1829 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 345)
  - Alfred Moore, 1799-1804 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 345)
  - John Marshall, 1801-1835 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 345)
  - William Johnson, 1804-1834 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 346)
  - Henry Brockholst Livingston, 1806-1823 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 346)
  - Thomas Todd, 1807-1826 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 346)
  - Joseph Story, 1811-1845 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 347)
  - Gabriel Duval, 1811-1835 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 347)
  - Smith Thompson, 1823-1843 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 348)
  - Robert Trimble, 1826-1828 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 348)
  - John McLean, 1829-1861 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 348)
  - Henry Baldwin, 1830-1844 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 348)
  - James M. Wayne, 1835-1867 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 349)
  - Roger B. Taney, 1836-1864 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 349)
  - John Catron, 1837-1865 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 349)
  - John McKinley, 1837-1852 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 350)
  - Peter V. Daniel, 1841-1860 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 350)
  - Samuel Nelson, 1845-1872 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 350)
  - Levi Woodbury, 1845-1851 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 350)
  - Robert C. Grier, 1846-1870 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 350)
  - Benjamin R. Curtis, 1851-1857 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 351)
  - John A. Campbell, 1853-1861 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 351)
  - Nathan Clifford, 1858-1881 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 351)
  - Noah H. Swayne, 1862-1881 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 351)
  - Samuel F. Miller, 1862-1890 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 351)
  - David Davis, 1862-1877 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 351)
  - Stephen J. Field, 1863-1897 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 351)
  - Salmon P. Chase, 1864-1873 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 351)
  - William Strong, 1870-1880 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 351)
  - Joseph P. Bradley, 1870-1892 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 352)
  - Ward Hunt, 1872-1882 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 352)
  - Morrison R. Waite, 1874-1888 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 352-353)
  - John M. Harlan, 1877-1891 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 353)
  - William B. Woods, 1880-1887 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 353)
  - Stanley Matthews, 1881-1889 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 354)
  - Horace Gray, 1881-1902 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 354)
  - Samuel Blatchford, 1882-1893 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 354)
  - Lucius Q. C. Lamar, 1888-1893 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 354)
  - Melville W. Fuller, 1888-1910 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 354)
  - David J. Brewer, 1889-1910 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 354)
  - Henry B. Brown, 1890-1906 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 354)
  - Howell E. Jackson, 1893-1895 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 354)
  - Edward D. White, 1894-1910 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 354)
  - Rufus W. Peckham, 1895-1909 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 354)
  - Charles E. Hughes, 1910-1916 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 354)
- Series XII: General Winfield Scott
  Portraits are arranged by leaf number.
  - Winfield Scott (Offsite-box 35, Folder 355-363)
- Series XIII: Havemeyer Inventories
  Arranged in alphabetical order, with non-print collections at the end. The inventories date from the 1940s to circa 1955.
  - Portrait Collections
    - Attorneys General (Offsite-box 36, Folder 364)
    - Calhoun, Clay, Webster (Offsite-box 36, Folder 365)
    - Interior, Secretaries of (Offsite-box 36, Folder 366)
    - Miscellaneous Portraits (Offsite-box 36, Folder 367)
    - Navy, Secretaries of (Offsite-box 36, Folder 368)
    - Postmasters General (Offsite-box 36, Folder 369)
    - Presidents, General (Offsite-box 36, Folder 370)
    - Presidents, Jackson (Offsite-box 36, Folder 371)
    - Presidents, Donated 1949 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 372)
    - Presidents, Donated 1950 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 373)
    - Scott, Winfield (Offsite-box 36, Folder 374)
    - States, Secretaries of (Offsite-box 36, Folder 375)
    - Supreme Court, Justices of (Offsite-box 36, Folder 376)
    - Treasury, Secretaries of (Offsite-box 36, Folder 377)
    - Vice Presidents (Offsite-box 36, Folder 378)
    - War, Secretaries of (Offsite-box 36, Folder 379)
    - Print Summary (Offsite-box 36, Folder 380)
  - Non-portrait Collections
    - Civil War letters (Offsite-box 36, Folder 381)
    - Engraved plates (Offsite-box 36, Folder 382)
    - Medals (Offsite-box 36, Folder 383)
    - Naval, miscellaneous (Offsite-box 36, Folder 384)
    - 1952 Donation (Offsite-box 36, Folder 385)
    - Winslow, Cameron McRae, letters (Offsite-box 36, Folder 386)